Rather than just saying sales calls
are ridiculous and you should never do
them,
let's look at some of the pros.
I'm going to steelman the argument.
To anyone that listens to what I say,
I actually don't mind.
I actually recommend sales calls
sometimes.
A video that I did with a one-to-one
student last week, name was Vicky, I
actually gave her a very short funnel.
She said to me she
was overwhelmed by the idea of email
marketing and landing
pages. I go, "Cool.
We don't have to have so many stages in
it.
We can go from socials, content,
straight onto a call."
And in her scenario, I
actually thought it
was a good idea because she was brand new.
And sometimes you're stared down the
barrel of building something
that could take
weeks or months,
or getting people to have a conversation
with you.
And of course, it'd be ridiculous to say,
"No, let's not onboard any new people for
weeks or months." So it
is perfectly plausible to take someone
from socials to
book a call.
There's nothing wrong with that.
But as you're going to find out later in
the video, you run into certain problems
if that's all you do.
I also agree for certain demographics,
it's very important.
Rewind to Vicky again.
She works with menopausal women.
I don't know menopausal women,
but I can assume
that they may just want to jump on
a call with a woman that's been through
what they've been through.
They can get a real-time sense of empathy
and understanding and be spoken through
what they're doing. Not to mention,
menopausal people now, who
are potentially in
their 40s and 50s, may have been in
that slight paradigm shift between
tech-savvy
people and my parents.
My mom doesn't even have a phone.
I also think for smaller creators,
say you've only got a few hundred
followers or
maybe even 1,000,
the sales call might be better because you
may not have the
gravitas nor the resources to be paying
for things like a landing page
or a squeeze
page or an email marketing platform.
So for smaller creators in your first six
months of business, there is a time for a
sales call.
But don't even call it a sales call.
Just have a conversation with your
prospect and map out everything
that you would
do for them. Then at the end,
just tell them how much it would cost
and what they
can expect working with you.
It's also very good to explain to someone
with what
you say that there's a money-back
guarantee so they can believe it.
There's also something
that I call the reverse sales call,
which I've spoken about
again before online a few times.
If you have a lead magnet
and you get a lot of
information from people,
you might get their Instagram, their name,
their number,
their job profession, whatever it is.
Let's say I, as a business coach,
I get hundreds of leads a day from YouTube
from
people wanting content critiques.
I could, if I wanted 10 new clients today,
find five people, spend five
minutes and record my screen. "Hi, John,
just got on to your Instagram.
Here are five things
that I would do to fix your business over
the next six months.
Here's a one-time offer.
I'd love to work with you." Out of five of
those, I reckon
three would buy. Now,
considering I charge several thousand
dollars for my
mentorship,
why don't I do 10 of those a day?
Well, because I'm marketing,
so I don't need to sell.
Those clients are going to come through
anyway, and I've automated the entire
system.
That's ultimately what I want for you.
Even if right now that seems daunting,
in a year's time,
if you're going to get the
growth that you want,
you're going to want these systems in
place